



in /kgchoy

778.829.9356

#### **PROFILE**

I specialize in user experience research and design, with a desire to get to know how current and potential users might use an interactive product throughout every step of the development process, from conceptualization to product evaluation. My overall passion for design compliments my expertise in web coding and programming, allowing me to translate my design ideas into reality. Finally, I have professional experience in marketing and communications.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Design	Programming & Web	Other Software & Platforms
Axure	HTML5/CSS3	Bootstrap
Balsamiq	JavaScript (libraries: jQuery, D3.js, three.js)	Git/GitHub
Illustrator	Java (including experience with Android APIs)	Amazon Web Services
InDesign	Python	Microsoft SQL Server
Photoshop	C++	Eloqua

# CONCEPTS & KNOWLEDGE

Interaction design Responsive web design Graphic and print design Wireframing & prototyping Desktop, mobile & web app development Agile development

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Email & Website Developer/Designer** (Co-op)

**ACTIVE Network** 

January 2014 - August 2014

Roles

- Designed and coded emails, forms, and landing pages in HTML/CSS, additionally using JavaScript and the Bootstrap framework when appropriate
- · Set them up for distribution and viewing using the Eloqua marketing automation software
- Created graphic assets for digital marketing materials
- Ensured all designs followed corporate branding standards

Outcomes

Created high-quality emails and landing pages while frequently working within tight deadlines. Contributed greatly to marketing and communications objectives, and drove leads and conversions.

#### **Communications Research Assistant** (Co-op)

**BCcampus** 

January 2013 – August 2013

Roles

- Coordinated a usability test of their corporate website; researched use cases, designed the test, recruited participants, and facilitated tests at their workplaces
- Facilitated a major reorganization of their Confluence corporate wiki after consulting with their staff, coordinated software tutorial sessions, and provided technical support
- Created a biweekly marketing newsletter using Campaign Monitor

Outcomes

Strengthened communication and collaboration between BCcampus and their users and stakeholders (academic faculty, administrators, and staff), plus internally between their teams of employees. My report of findings and recommendations after the usability test guided the design of their new responsive website.

**Kevin Choy** kevinchoy.ca

## FREELANCE WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Graphic Designer and Front-End Web Designer**

New Dawn Immigration May 2016 – Present

I am working on a complete branding redesign for an immigration services firm. As a project in progress, I have finished ideating and creating logos and business card designs; my next responsibility will be to design an entirely new version of the website using WordPress. I expect to complete this project by mid to late June.

#### **UX Course Projects**

### UX, UI, and Interaction Designer & Researcher

**Community Builder** 

October 2015 - December 2015

Our team of four developed the interface and interactions for an Android app that allowed people to organize, search, and volunteer for community events within their neighbourhoods, promoting physical community engagement.

Roles

- Created scenarios, personas, and a journey map to explore user goals and task flows
- Rapidly developed and refined interface designs, ranging from low-fidelity paper wireframes to high-fidelity Axure prototypes, on a weekly cycle using the agile methodology, taking into account design critiques and usability test results
- Created a usability test plan and its tasks, and facilitated the tests

## **Usability Researcher and Usability Test Designer & Coordinator**

Notif

January 2015 – April 2015

In our team of four, we conceptualized and created a prototype for Notif, a concept mapping tool targeted towards the academic teaching and learning domain.

Roles

- Researched the types of problems faced by instructors and students, as well as potential solutions
- Developed use cases, UML diagrams, and class diagrams to understand how users might accomplish a task and how the system as a whole would work, revising as needed using the spiral model
- Facilitated a usability test session involving an interactive Flash prototype

#### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

#### Vice President of Education

**Burnaby Mountain Toastmasters** 

October 2014 - Present

The goal of our Toastmasters club at SFU is to help members improve their public speaking skills in a fun, friendly, and supportive environment. I monitor each member's educational goals, coordinate the weekly club meetings and member roles, and ensure that new members receive an orientation to the club and are assigned a mentor. I have also served as a mentor myself.

#### **EDUCATION**

# B.Sc. in Interactive Arts & Technology (Concentration in Interactive Systems), Minor in Computing Science

**Simon Fraser University** 

September 2009 – December 2015

As a graduate from the School of Interactive Arts & Technology, I learned the skills and tools to not only create both elegant and functional designs, but to also build the technologies and experiences that increasingly shape our lives. My concentration, Interactive Systems, focuses on the interaction between computer systems and users.